<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pointlander</title>
    <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Pointlander</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 19:44:37 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Three Pathes to the Singularity</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/three-pathes-to-the-singularity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 19:44:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/three-pathes-to-the-singularity/</guid>
      <description>AGI, but machine learning can get us there. Machine learning is like the steam engine: good enough but not perfect. AGI is like a jet engine. Complete simulation of any material. Everything would get better and cheaper really fast. Quantum Gravity becoming a solved problem. This could lead to flying cars and real space ships.  So, there are several ways in which the singularity can happen, and in my opinion the above three things are happening at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capitalism vs Marxism Is Last Century</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/capitalism-vs-marxism-is-last-century/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 19:36:23 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/capitalism-vs-marxism-is-last-century/</guid>
      <description>Capitalism vs Marxism was the economic conflict of the last century. The economic conflict of this century is programmers vs everybody else. Programmers create billion dollar business that destroy jobs, and other programmers try to destroy those businesses with open source software. A good examples of this is RISC-V destroying ARM&amp;rsquo;s business. Most significantly, using crypto currency programmers tried to destroy all governments on earth.
Currently, working from home is taking off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Vacuum Gradients</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/quantum-vacuum-gradients/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 22:23:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/quantum-vacuum-gradients/</guid>
      <description>Update: See: Electrostatic accelerated electrons within symmetric capacitors during field emission condition events exert bidirectional propellant-less thrust and Horizon Engineers.
MEMS Chips that measure the force of the quantum vacuum have been produced. Should the measured force be the same in all frames of reference? From the standpoint of general relativity the answer is yes, but this means one frame of reference may measure a weaker quantum vacuum in another frame of reference that is moving faster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mach Energy</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/mach-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 19:29:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/mach-energy/</guid>
      <description>Mach Energy is a source of energy based on Mach&amp;rsquo;s principle; in particular it is based on Einstein&amp;rsquo;s interpretation of Mach&amp;rsquo;s principle. In a single particle universe the particle&amp;rsquo;s mass can&amp;rsquo;t be measured, and other things can&amp;rsquo;t be measured such as time. As a consequence the conservation of energy may not hold in a single particle universe. The vast empty regions of our universe may have some of the properties of the single particle universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grapevine</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/grapevine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 19:56:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/grapevine/</guid>
      <description>Update: See: Grapevine for reference implementation and Hacker News.
Grapevine is a distributed protocol for replacing twitter like systems. It is composed of nodes that add a proof of work over a message and nonces from previous nodes, so the proof of works stack up as messages pass through nodes. Messages with a higher total cost have a higher probability of being forwarded to the next node. Individual nodes decide the cost of the proof of work they add to the message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Could Be Casimir Effect</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/could-be-casimir-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 21:39:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/could-be-casimir-effect/</guid>
      <description>From nextbigfuture: Circuit Design Claimed to Harvest Tiny But Infinite Power From Brownian Motion. This device is like Maxwell&amp;rsquo;s demon, but Maxwell&amp;rsquo;s demon has been theoretically shown not to generate over unity energy. I think the source of energy is from the Casimir effect. Thermal vibrations bend the graphene slightly, and then the Casimir effect bends the graphene some more. This results in the conductivity of the graphene decreasing which reduces the Casimir force.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetry in Time</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/asymmetry-in-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 23:13:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/asymmetry-in-time/</guid>
      <description>Update: See: The EmDrive Just Won&amp;rsquo;t Die.
From nextbigfuture: DARPA Laser Version of EMDrive Has a Test Result Better Than Commercial Ion Drive. These devices are composed of an asymmetric resonant chamber driven by a laser. I think the asymmetry in space causes momentum to not be conserved, but there is also asymmetry in time. I think turning the laser on and off randomly could improve the performance of the device by creating asymmetry in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symmetry Breaking and Conservation</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/symmetry-breaking-and-conservation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 19:48:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/symmetry-breaking-and-conservation/</guid>
      <description>From nextbigfuture: Mach Effect Propulsion Levels Becoming Significant and Reliable, so it appears momentum is not conserved under certain conditions. And Casimir effect experiments demonstrate energy is not conserved. This means that the universe is asymmetric in some manner because conservation doesn&amp;rsquo;t always work. Spontaneous symmetry breaking describes how the universe could be in an asymmetric state yet still be symmetric overall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Computation</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/atomic-computation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 20:00:43 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/atomic-computation/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post I put forward the idea that an atom could be computationally driven to decay. Such an idea would be classified as a Low Energy Nuclear Reaction. This means that nuclear decay is a form of computation with an output of 0 or 1, decay or don&amp;rsquo;t decay. What is the nature of this computation? Quantum computation is known to be unitary, so it appears the nature of atoms is to conserve information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Halting</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/atomic-halting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 21:01:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/atomic-halting/</guid>
      <description>The entropy of state changes of a halted program are low. To find the inputs to a program that cause halting a cost function of entropy of state changes could be used. (Apparently quantum computers can solve the halting problem via nextbigfuture.) I believe what holds an atom together is computation. It is a computation that has a high entropy of state changes. An atom could be induced to decay with the right inputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating Fact Based Articles</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/generating-fact-based-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 21:32:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/generating-fact-based-articles/</guid>
      <description>Recently there as been much buzz about a natural language machine learning model called GPT-3. OpenAI is going to create an API for this technology. I have signed for access to this API for the purpose of generating news articles. I want to feed facts into the model and see if it generates good news articles. The facts could be stored in a relational and searchable database. The user could query this database, get some facts, and then use the OpenAI API to generate a news article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RIT Time Lapse</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/rit-time-lapse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 21:31:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/rit-time-lapse/</guid>
      <description>One of the first pieces of software that I developed in 2000 was a script that captured images from a web cam and set them as my desktop. I also saved these images to disk. I have turned these images into a time lapse video of RIT which can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RIT SME Robots</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/rit-sme-robots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 21:31:22 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/rit-sme-robots/</guid>
      <description>While going to school at RIT I was a member of the SME robotics club. I developed software for the two robots we created. This first robot was built in 2000 for the purpose of moving parts around a factory floor. Video of this robot can be found here. We continued building robots, and the next robot we built in 2003 was an outdoors robot in the form of a tank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Nature of God</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/on-the-nature-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 20:57:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/on-the-nature-of-god/</guid>
      <description>Update: See: Global Consciousness Project.
Einstein said &amp;lsquo;God does not play dice&amp;rsquo;, but could it be that God is the only source of truly random information. This would mean that the randomness of quantum mechanics is from God&amp;rsquo;s perspective non-random. God&amp;rsquo;s primary means of intervening could be in the quantum world. In Objective-collapse theory a source of randomness is used to drive wave collapse, so this means that God solves the measurement problem in quantum mechanics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merging of Copenhagen and Everett</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/merging-of-copenhagen-and-everett/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 21:28:29 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/merging-of-copenhagen-and-everett/</guid>
      <description>The Copenhagen interpretation holds that there is only one reality and multiple possibilities, and the Everett interpretation holds that there are multiple realities with each corresponding to a possibility. It is possible to merge these two interpretations of quantum mechanics by allowing multiple realities to merge into one. Different realities are allowed to merge if the merge is unitary, that is time reversible. At the end of time all realities are merged together, and at the beginning of time there was one reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratic Capitalism</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/democratic-capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 13:27:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/democratic-capitalism/</guid>
      <description>The current economy of the world is bifurcated into two parts: a post singularity economy and a pre singularity economy. The post singularity economy is often called &amp;ldquo;tech&amp;rdquo;. The pre singularity economy includes things like housing, medicine, and education. As deflation occurs in the post singularity economy money moves into the pre singularity economy. This is why housing, medicine, and education are getting more expensive as televisions are getting better and cheaper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everett Activation Function</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/everett-activation-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 20:47:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/everett-activation-function/</guid>
      <description>Update: Example available here.
The Everett interpretation of quantum mechanics holds that there are infinitely many universes. The universe branches with each measurement. The act of measurement is similar to the activation functions used in neural networks. The output of a neuron could be fed into two activation functions. The ReLU and its complement could be used: max(0, x) and min(0, x). When added together in a neuron: w1 * max(0, x) + w2 * min(0, x) = x (for w1 = w2 = 1) which is the identity function, so gradient descent decides if the Everett activation function is an identity function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Genetic Optimization</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/quantum-genetic-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 17:30:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/quantum-genetic-optimization/</guid>
      <description>Update: Simulation available here.
In Quantum Computing with the Human Brain I introduce the idea of quantum genetic optimization:
 Genetic optimization uses simulated evolution to solve problems. For instance, it could be used to factor numbers. In this case the genome is two numbers: a &amp;amp; b, and the fitness function is |n - (a * b)|. In the case of a quantum implementation the genome would be the quantum computer configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Mechanical Placebo Effect</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/quantum-mechanical-placebo-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 22:21:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/quantum-mechanical-placebo-effect/</guid>
      <description>There is a theory that the human brain is a quantum computer. I believe this idea is connected to the placebo effect. Chemistry is quantum mechanics and placebos are typically sugar pills. Is it quantum information that causes the effect? Is information on its own sufficient? Can faith heal? If this is the case the government should spend lots money on positive ads. This would be more useful than helicopter money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Communication</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/quantum-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 15:25:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/quantum-communication/</guid>
      <description>I propose a quantum communication system using quantum computation. In this system there are two pools of qubits: a sender and a receiver. Some of the qubits of the sender are entangled with the qubits of the receiver. Three entanglement configurations are selected: A, B and C; A and B are configurations of the sender, and C is the configuration of the receiver. The overall system has two configurations which result in known qubit states with high probability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Computing With the Human Brain</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/quantum-computing-with-the-human-brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 21:40:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/quantum-computing-with-the-human-brain/</guid>
      <description>Genetic optimization uses simulated evolution to solve problems. For instance, it could be used to factor numbers. In this case the genome is two numbers: a &amp;amp; b, and the fitness function is |n - (a * b)|. In the case of a quantum implementation the genome would be the quantum computer configuration. The configuration would be evolved until the number is factored. This system searches for a quantum program that factors the number.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Cold Fusion and Quantum Mechanics</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/on-cold-fusion-and-quantum-mechanics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 15:38:05 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/on-cold-fusion-and-quantum-mechanics/</guid>
      <description>I have been reading Einstein&amp;rsquo;s Unfinished Revolution, The Search for What Lies Beyond the Quantum by Lee Smolin, and the chapter &amp;lsquo;Physical Collapse of the Quantum State&amp;rsquo; caught my attention:
 One consequence is that energy is no longer precisely conserved. A metal block should slowly heat up as a result of all the collapses the wave functions of its atoms undergo.
 A similar claim is made in the article Objective-collapse theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything as a Quantum Neural Network</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/everything-as-a-quantum-neural-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 20:36:02 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/everything-as-a-quantum-neural-network/</guid>
      <description>I have been reading Penrose&amp;rsquo;s The Emperor&amp;rsquo;s New Mind, and about half way through he points out that quantum systems are linear until they are measured. From a machine learning standpoint this is not good. Linear artificial neural networks are of limited use and can only be used to model the simplest data sets. When a non-linear transform (activation function) is added after each linear layer in a neural network then it is able to solve difficult problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synchronicity Network</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/synchronicity-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 22:10:30 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/synchronicity-network/</guid>
      <description>Unlike the principal of flight, the principal of consciousness is an unsolved problem. Before airplanes, people tried to build flying machines that emulated birds, but it turned out that replicating the complexity of birds was unnecessary. We still can&amp;rsquo;t build machines that are as complex as a bird.
Synchronicity is a concept which holds that events are &amp;ldquo;meaningful coincidences&amp;rdquo; if they occur with no causal relationship yet seem to be meaningfully related.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sync</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/sync/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 16:54:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/sync/</guid>
      <description>Sync is the mathematics of how independent systems can synchronize their state. (Hacker News discussion) When multiple metronomes are placed on the same table they sync up their ticking over time, but if more metronomes are placed on the table they don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily sync up. The additional metronomes can form their own sync clusters. I think sync can serve as a more general theory of music, explain why there are different types of particles in the universe, and explain high temperature superconductors (and perhaps lead to room temperature superconductors).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artemis Neural Network Scaling</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/artemis-neural-network-scaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 21:52:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/artemis-neural-network-scaling/</guid>
      <description>Artemis has a powerful wireless technology called pCell. It appears that pCell might have a high computational cost resulting in scaling issues. They might be able to solve this problem by replacing portions of their algorithm with neural networks. If they have an accurate simulator, they could even replace the entirety of their algorithm with deep reinforcement learning. This could be a good application of analog computer based neural networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unify Quantum Mechanics and General Relativity With Computation</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/unify-quantum-mechanics-and-general-relativity-with-computation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 21:57:11 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/unify-quantum-mechanics-and-general-relativity-with-computation/</guid>
      <description>It is known that quantum mechanics is Turing complete. If the Einstein field equations are Turing complete, then a &amp;ldquo;relativity computer&amp;rdquo; could be built. (It is known that some differential equations are Turing complete.) Unification of quantum mechanics and general relativity is then a matter of converting quantum programs to relativity programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Models</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/scalable-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 21:43:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/scalable-models/</guid>
      <description>The author of Gorgonia, a neural network library, had an interesting Strange Loop talk about reimplementing AlphaGo. The problem they ran into is that it would have cost them $70,000 to train a competitive model, so they focused on training their algorithm for games with a smaller board. What if a small neural network could be scaled to work on a larger board? The approach that I propose is based on program synthesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRDTs and Open Source</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/crdts-and-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 21:29:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/crdts-and-open-source/</guid>
      <description>CRDTs, conflict free replicated data types, are data structures that can be synchronized across an unreliable network with consistency guarantees. Here is a talk on CRTDs from Martin Kleppmann. His group has produced a CRTD library called automerge which gives an application a JSON-like data structure that is replicated across multiple machines. Why is this significant? Open Source currently can&amp;rsquo;t compete with SAAS because users want their data backed up and available on all devices, and unfortunately servers cost money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noninvasive Neural Activation (or how to hack the human brain)</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/noninvasive-neural-activation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 22:13:28 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/noninvasive-neural-activation/</guid>
      <description>There are noninvasive approaches for reading neural activations from the brain, but a noninvasive method for writing into the brain currently doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist. The value of write capability can be seen from this article. The article describes how neural activity was transferred from better trained rats to rats with less training. Then the rats with less training performed like the better trained rats. The rats had electrodes placed inside their brains, but I think it is possible to do such an experiment on humans without the electrodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Free Energy</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/one-free-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 11:09:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/one-free-energy/</guid>
      <description>In the paper Mining Energy In An Expanding Universe a source of free energy is described. In an expanding universe free energy can be produced by connecting widely separated bodies with strings. Another way of producing free energy is the Casimir effect. This works by placing two conducting plates parallel to each other. A net force between the plates is then produced. So, there are two known ways of producing free energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nash Consciousness</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/nash-consciousness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 21:58:36 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/nash-consciousness/</guid>
      <description>There is an interesting article on the computer scientist Constantinos Daskalakis. The article talks about his work on Nash equilibrium, machine learning, and neurology. The obvious idea here is that perhaps neuron behavior could be explained by game theory. Each neuron seeks an optimal strategy for playing some game. After all organisms operate through competition. This could mean that consciousness is a Nash equilibrium. In order to create AGI all we need to do is figure out what game neurons are playing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Auto Merge</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/smart-auto-merge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 22:43:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/smart-auto-merge/</guid>
      <description>Wikipedia edit wars are a well known tragedy of the commons problem. What is needed is an ownership model similar to Github, but then which version of an article is the correct version? Machine learning could be used to produce one correct article from all of the different article versions. The different article versions would be auto merged together. The Transformer machine learning algorithm could solve the auto merge problem: Generating Wikipedia by Summarizing Long Sequences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mind Pod</title>
      <link>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/mind-pod/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 14:12:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.snodgrass.xyz/posts/mind-pod/</guid>
      <description>Mind pod is an iPod that attaches to both your brain and ears. The purpose is to generate music from your brain activity. There are two enabling technologies required for this idea to work. One enabling technology is a wearable brain sensor comparable to an MRI machine: Openwater, and the second enabling technology is a neural network capable of generating music: SampleRNN. Music generated from SampleRNN can be found here. To create music from brain activity all one has to do is record the brain activity from a user listening to some music and then use the recorded brain activity and the corresponding music to train a neural network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
