<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Pointlander</title>
    <link>https://pointlander.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Pointlander</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 22:13:28 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pointlander.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Noninvasive Neural Activation (or how to hack the human brain)</title>
      <link>https://pointlander.github.io/posts/noninvasive-neural-activation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 22:13:28 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pointlander.github.io/posts/noninvasive-neural-activation/</guid>
      <description>There are noninvasive approaches for reading neural activations from the brain, but a noninvasive method for writing into the brain currently doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist. The value of write capability can be seen from this article. The article describes how neural activity was transferred from better trained rats to rats with less training. Then the rats with less training performed like the better trained rats. The rats had electrodes placed inside their brains, but I think it is possible to do such an experiment on humans without the electrodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Free Energy</title>
      <link>https://pointlander.github.io/posts/one-free-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 11:09:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pointlander.github.io/posts/one-free-energy/</guid>
      <description>In the paper Mining Energy In An Expanding Universe a source of free energy is described. In an expanding universe free energy can be produced by connecting widely separated bodies with strings. Another way of producing free energy is the Casimir effect. This works by placing two conducting plates parallel to each other. A net force between the plates is then produced. So, there are two known ways of producing free energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nash Consciousness</title>
      <link>https://pointlander.github.io/posts/nash-consciousness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 21:58:36 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pointlander.github.io/posts/nash-consciousness/</guid>
      <description>There is an interesting article on the computer scientist Constantinos Daskalakis. The article talks about his work on Nash equilibrium, machine learning, and neurology. The obvious idea here is that perhaps neuron behavior could be explained by game theory. Each neuron seeks an optimal strategy for playing some game. After all organisms operate through competition. This could mean that consciousness is a Nash equilibrium. In order to create AGI all we need to do is figure out what game neurons are playing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Auto Merge</title>
      <link>https://pointlander.github.io/posts/smart-auto-merge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 22:43:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pointlander.github.io/posts/smart-auto-merge/</guid>
      <description>Wikipedia edit wars are a well known tragedy of the commons problem. What is needed is an ownership model similar to Github, but then which version of an article is the correct version? Machine learning could be used to produce one correct article from all of the different article versions. The different article versions would be auto merged together. The Transformer machine learning algorithm could solve the auto merge problem: Generating Wikipedia by Summarizing Long Sequences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mind Pod</title>
      <link>https://pointlander.github.io/posts/mind-pod/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 14:12:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pointlander.github.io/posts/mind-pod/</guid>
      <description>Mind pod is an iPod that attaches to both your brain and ears. The purpose is to generate music from your brain activity. There are two enabling technologies required for this idea to work. One enabling technology is a wearable brain sensor comparable to an MRI machine: Openwater, and the second enabling technology is a neural network capable of generating music: SampleRNN. Music generated from SampleRNN can be found here. To create music from brain activity all one has to do is record the brain activity from a user listening to some music and then use the recorded brain activity and the corresponding music to train a neural network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>